Adriana Paiva

+1 416-523-0873 | adrianapaivausa@icloud.com | Toronto, ON, Canada Portfolio: <u>itsadrianapaiva.com</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/itsadrianapaiva</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/itsadrianapaiva

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer specialized in web applications, backed by **8 years** in project management and digital strategy within the **USA** marketing industry. Implemented and developed marketing projects with **99%** client satisfaction and achieved **58%** annual ROI growth, showcasing a high level of adaptability and client focus. Expertise in **Front-end** development using **TypeScript**, **React.js and Node.js.**

CORE COMPETENCIES

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript | TypeScript | Python

FRAMEWORKS: React.js | Next.js | Express.js

BACK-END: Node.js | REST APIs

DATABASES & DATA: SQL | MySQL | MongoDB

DEVELOPER TOOLS: Git | GitHub | Google Cloud Services **MARKETING STACK**: Google Analytics | SEO | Figma | Slack

SPEAKING LANGUAGES: Portuguese (C2) | English (C2) | Spanish (B1)

PROJECTS

Construction Web Application

TypeScript, React.js, Node.js - Current

Developing an estimate calculator and invoice generator which can increase in **80%** stakeholders productivity and streamline customer acquisition.

Brainwave Web Page

TypeScript, React.js, Node.js - 2024

Implemented advanced UI/UX design principles increasing awareness on an AI digital product.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Independent Consultant - Toronto, Canada | May 2024 - Present

- Designed and implemented **20+** end-to-end web applications ensuring seamless interaction between **front- end** and **back-end** systems.
- Contribute to **open source** projects on GitHub by developing features, fixing bugs, and improving documentation.
- Debugged, enhanced and maintained applications, driving continuous improvements and delivering an exceptional **user experience** across the development lifecycle.

Creative Director & Digital Strategist

Independent Consultant - Texas, United States | 2016 - 2024

- Implemented data-driven strategies driving a 20% improvement in client conversion rates.
- Collaborated with over **168 teams** throughout the years to execute **omni-channel marketing** initiatives.
- Maintained 8-17% repeat business rate over 8 years, demonstrating strong client satisfaction.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Full-Stack Development | 2024

FreeCodeCamp - USA

Bachelor of Science | 2012 - 2014

Major: Mechanical Engineering

Pontifícia Universidade Católica - MG/Brazil